PETER SCHALKWIJK

359-1111 Japan Saitama-ken, Tokorozawa-shi Midori-cho 3-50-6 Mobile: +81-90-7255-9969 Home & fax: +81-4-2939-8056 Email: peter.s@kzd.biglobe.ne.jp

SUMMARY

I am an experienced Sales & Business Development Executive, representing local entities and business units of large US and European companies; successful in selling new technologies in the Japanese and Asian markets. I have managed the P&L of a combination of top-line and project-based businesses, setting up a sales and engineering organization, driving multi-year growth through expanding markets and a portfolio of Video-, IT-, and consumer electronics-related products. I also have a strong technical background with an extensive Japan and Asia experience. Demonstrated successes:

- New Business Development
- Executive Account Coverage
- Managing Sales and Engineering Teams
- Startup Activities and Organization
- Direct Sales and Channel Management
- Localization and Product Development

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CISCO SYSTEMS G.K., Tokyo

(Acquisition of Scientific Atlanta Inc. in 2006)

2007 - 2014

Business Development Manager, Connected Devices Business Unit

2008 - 2014

Responsible for the business development of Cisco's cable modems, and connected gateway products and solutions; covering all aspects of the business, the mission was to expand the market reach and portfolio utilizing the infrastructure and capabilities of Cisco in each and every market in Australia, Asia, China, and Japan

- Increased annual bookings from \$13M in FY08 to \$52M in FY14 with an accumulated (FY09 to FY14) bookings number of \$233M and revenue of \$224M; shipped a total of 5.8M devices into this market with an average gross margin well above the company average
- Full responsibility and ownership of defining the market and product strategy; realized coverage in every country, involving the assignment of new partners and distributors, including the execution of supply and customer contracts
- Introduction of product roadmaps (including IPTV and OTT) and new concepts (such as connected home) to customers, partners and internal sales and engineering teams
- Coordination of project development and localization for specific markets involving the BU and Regional management, product management, hardware and software engineering, ODM engineering and manufacturing teams, and in-country sales and engineering teams
- Coordination and escalation of software- and hardware-related issues from the field deployment and customer acceptance process

Regional Manager, Service Provider Operations

2007

A transition year, taking full responsibility for the integration of the Scientific Atlanta Japan organization and activities into Cisco Japan and accommodated a limited restructuring

SCIENTIFIC ATLANTA, INC., Tokyo

2000 - 2006

(A leading video and data solution provider; revenue \$1.9 billion (FY05), 7652 employees)

SA Japan KK Representative Director (Country Manager)

Responsible for reactivating the local legal entity in Japan, establishing a sales / support organization, and providing executive account and partner coverage at the CxO level; by capturing the different market transitions and compelling events, was able to introduce a full new portfolio of products, all successfully deployed and covering all market segments

- Accumulated over \$300M in bookings over the period of FY01 to FY07, selling a broad range of products and solutions to the cable operators and telecommunication industry
- Established a new sales office and legal entity in 2000 and built and managed a sales, engineering, and marketing organization total 14 persons
- Accomplished the development contracts, including NRE funding, for digital set-top-box solutions with major cable operators in Japan; contributed to this development effort by hiring local experts, participating in local committees, contracting with local developers and consultants, and by setting up a local development lab
- Successfully sold various new distribution systems into the local market, such as encoding and network equipment (fiber, satellite, IP-backbone) for the distribution of hundreds of video channels, Hybrid fiber/coax distribution equipment, and Cable TV Internet solutions (CMTS router / gateways, consumer premises equipment)

Philips Japan KK, Tokyo

1995 - 2000

(A global conglomerate, FY2000: 38 Billion in revenue, 219,429 employees worldwide)

Country Manager, Philips Broadband Networks

1998 - 2000

A start-up activity to introduce Philip's cable tv solutions into the local market; managed a small sales support group, introduced various new technologies, and accommodated an annual sales of \$4M

Business Development Manager, Philips Japan

1995 - 1997

Responsible for the business development of the various initiatives Philips was undertaking to cover the full media value chain of content creation, distribution, and consumer devices; responsible for marketing and sales execution of PC monitors and notebooks; evaluated the possibility of investment in the CATV industry through local partnership

Dutch Ministry of Economic Affairs, Tokyo

1990 - 1995

(With representative offices in the major countries for trade and science promotion)

Science Attaché to the Royal Netherlands Embassy in Tokyo

Consultancy for companies, universities, research institutes, and government; facilitating an increase of science and technology exchange between the Netherlands and Japan

EDUCATION

EMBA, Aoyama Gakuin University, Graduate School of International Management	2007 - 2008
Engineering Degree (ir.), Technical University Delft, Electrical Engineering	1982 - 1989
Fujitsu Research Laboratory, Kawasaki, Japan (as a research student)	1987 - 1988
Partial 1st and 2nd year at University of Leiden, Faculty of Japanese Language	1986 - 1987